<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theoretical-issues on </title>
    <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theoretical-issues on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Issues</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hype about ZERO and Its Influence on the Conservation and Presentation of Early Kinetic Works</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/12-heydenreich_giebeler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/12-heydenreich_giebeler/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In 1958, in search of a new artistic beginning—a Stunde Null, or “zero hour”—Otto Piene (1928–2014) and Heinz Mack (b. 1931) founded the artist magazine ZERO, which was later to give its name to an international art movement. In 1961 Günther Uecker (b. 1930) began to collaborate closely with Piene and Mack. They quickly gained considerable popularity through their light-kinetics, and they initiated numerous projects that involved other artists such as Jean Tinguely, Lucio Fontana, and Yves Klein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Multiples</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/13-plante/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/13-plante/</guid>
      <description>In 1966, Julio Le Parc represented Argentina in the Venice Biennale (fig. 13.1) and received the international grand prize in painting. According to the reviews, his space was one of the most visited.1 As the appeal of kinetic art continued to grow and draw crowds to museums, kinetic artworks seemed to meet the most ambitious objective of the avant-garde: to integrate art and life.
Kineticism2 was an international trend composed of different groups of artists who were in contact with one another, including the Groupe de Recherche d’Art Visuel (GRAV) in France, Gruppo T and Gruppo N in Italy, ZERO in Germany, Dwizjenije in Moscow, and USCO in New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collection of Nicolas Schöffer</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/14-dhaenens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/14-dhaenens/</guid>
      <description>Into the Artist’s Studio: From Kinetic to Cybernetic With more than 600 objects, the collection of Nicolas Schöffer (Hungarian, 1912–1992) is nearly complete. Currently installed in his Paris studio, it contains most of his unique artworks and at least one work from each of his series. In addition to paintings, drawings, archival materials, and plans, the collection is composed of kinetic, but mostly cybernetic, sculptures by the artist (fig. 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Pretty Good for the 21st Century”</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/15-brobbel_rees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/keepitmoving/theoretical-issues/15-brobbel_rees/</guid>
      <description>The New Zealand–born Len Lye (1901–1980) remains one of the most enigmatic of modernist artists. Leaving his homeland in his mid-twenties to seek out less provincial pastures, Lye traveled between Australia and Samoa, becoming familiar with aboriginal and Pacific cultures before arriving in London in 1926, where he was immediately welcomed by the British avant-garde. Several years exhibiting sculpture, painting, and photography with the Seven and Five Society,1 followed by an off-kilter relationship with the British Surrealists, are secondary to his career at the vanguard of experimental cinema.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>